66 Ranchview Dr. Nanaimo BC, Canada V9X1X9 +1(250)591-3784 email:jason@typi.ca twitter:@NeedTungsten

Profile

I am a versatile software developer with over 20 years experience. I have been working remotely for Seattle-based companies since 2012. I have experience working with large codebases, running large clusters of machines, and delivering timely and reliable updates to customers with minimal disruption. I have experience leading teams and mentoring junior engineers. I have a varied background in many different languages and systems and an insatiable curiosity to find out how things work.

Experience

Prompt.io — Chatbox

Founding Engineer

Seattle, WA (Remote)

2014 - Present

Our team built a cluster of Java-based services and a TypeScript frontend serving as a scalable platform for messaging and customer service. It is flexible, scriptable, and ties into many third-party services. Thousands of customers rely on it for their operations and it has handled peaks of over a million customer messages per day.

Interesting problems I worked on: "low-code" micro-app toolkit, application security, time & date handling, character encoding, distributed consensus (RAFT), API design, release management

Jawfish Games

Lead iOS Developer, Founding Engineer

Seattle, WA (Remote)

2012 - 2014

Our focus was on casual real-time multiplayer tournament games. We developed original games and modified existing turn-by-turn game types to work in a real-time player vs. player setting. This meant building a distributed messaging platform, game server host, and matchmaking service. I ran the iOS team building the front end and also wrote server side game logic. Our game MatchUp which was a suite of tournament games hit the Top 10 in the iOS App Store. Interesting problems I worked on: game design, custom binary protocols, code generation, animation scheduling, complicated team dynamics, multi-architecture RNG synchronization

Full Tilt Poker

Software Developer

Edmonton, Alberta

2008 - 2011

FullTilt Poker acquired BioTools in 2008. The main development office was in Dublin, Ireland. We operated as a skunkworks/R&D division in Edmonton, Canada. Our largest project was a tool for players to view and analyze the history of all the hands they had played. In addition to this development work I ran the build-out of the distributed database system underlying it. Later, I ran a project to create a simplified poker game client for android phones.

Interesting problems I worked on: multi-terabyte binary datasets, distributed databases, user interface design, server hardware build-out

BioTools Inc.

Operations Manager, Developer

Edmonton, Alberta

2004 - 2008

We started with a suite of Bioinformatics tools for genome and protein sequence analysis. We shifted course to produce Poker Academy. This was a learning and training tool similar in spirit to Chessmaster, but for Poker. Along with development work. mostly in Java, I ran the datacenter, which hosted online play-money poker tournaments, supported the retail software sales and hosted a vibrant community of players.

Interesting problems I worked on: game opponent AI (non neural-net based), retail software distribution (online and physical multi-language), data center management and security, community engagement

Alberta Functional Language

Assessment Battery

Edmonton, Alberta 2003 - 2004

This was a project for a linguistics professor at the University of Alberta. I created a small domain specific language and a system for creating clinical reports. You would feed it raw test scores and a report template and it would perform statistical analyses and output a formatted report.

Interesting problems I worked on: language design, parsing, statistical analysis

Edmonton Public School Board

Software Developer

Software Developer

Edmonton, Alberta

2000 - 2002

School computer technicians were using ad-hoc mechanisms such as spreadsheets to keep track of various bits of data such as network information. I imported these into a database and built a web-based tool to make this easier. We later packaged this up as a "web portal" that was sold as a tool to other school districts.

Interesting problems I worked on: import of messy data sets, location mapping, network configuration tools

Education

University of Alberta BSc Neuroscience, 2003

University of Alberta BSc Evolutionary Biology, 2001

Hobbies

Cooking, Backpacking, Kayaking, Electronics, Parametric CAD & 3D Printing